<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>security on Blog of Serhat M. Dündar | Ruby, Rails, Golang, PostgreSQL, AWS, Security</title>
    <link>https://www.serhatdundar.com/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on Blog of Serhat M. Dündar | Ruby, Rails, Golang, PostgreSQL, AWS, Security</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.serhatdundar.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.serhatdundar.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 18:30:19 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.serhatdundar.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Primite Hashing Function in Go</title>
      <link>https://www.serhatdundar.com/posts/a-primite-hashing-function-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 18:30:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serhatdundar.com/posts/a-primite-hashing-function-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Cryptographic hash functions are complex mathematical calculations. Therefore understanding them requires a considerable amount of time and patience. However, they all have things in common: an input, a cryptographic algorithm, and an output.
Recently, I had a chance to study some popular cryptographic hash functions, such as MD5 and SHA-1, and tried to understand how they really work. Wikipedia pages I linked include a considerable amount of information already, and more can be found online, but what I want to do was understand similarities between them and write my own primitive hashing function in Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSL/TLS Handshake, Hybrid Encryption and Public Key Infrastructure (PKI)</title>
      <link>https://www.serhatdundar.com/posts/ssl-tls-handshake-hybrid-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 14:00:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serhatdundar.com/posts/ssl-tls-handshake-hybrid-encryption/</guid>
      <description>Hybrid Encryption: Symmetric and Asymmetric Encryption Combined Both symmetric and asymmetric encryption has advantages and disadvantages. So, which one should we use? Well, nowadays we often use them together. Asymmetric encryption is often used to exchange private keys between parties securely. In other words, parties who would communicate establish an asymmetric encryption protocol in the beginning just to exchange private keys. When the private key exchange is completed, they keep communicating by using symmetric encryption - which is faster than asymmetric encryption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symmetric and Asymmetric Encryption</title>
      <link>https://www.serhatdundar.com/posts/symmetric-and-asymmetric-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 14:00:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serhatdundar.com/posts/symmetric-and-asymmetric-encryption/</guid>
      <description>Symmetric Encryption (Private Key Cryptography) In symmetric encryption only a single key, in other words, a private key is used to encrypt and decrypt a message. Symmetric encryption is also known as &amp;ldquo;Private Key Cryptography&amp;rdquo; as the whole encryption is only based on a private key.
Some popular symetric encryption algorithms are:
   Algorithm Cipher Key Size Block/State Size Popularity Notes     AES Block 128, 192, or 256 bits 128 bits 1 The best one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
